capitalone.ca 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy

### Summary

Your privacy is important to us. The personal information we collect about you is managed in accordance with this Policy.

We collect information you provide to us when you register or apply for one of our products or services, visit or use our website or apps, interact with us, or engage with us in any way.

This information may be used for specific purposes, including:

  * To contact you
  * To authenticate you
  * To continually assess your creditworthiness
  * To service you
  * To make improvements
  * To prevent fraud
  * To serve you offers, advertising and marketing
  * To report
  * As required by law 

We will not add your name to marketing campaigns for the first 30 days after the opening of your account to give you an opportunity to opt out of mail, email and phone marketing. You can also opt out of the use of cookies for Online Behavioural Advertising.

We may share your information with third parties who help us to assess, process, collect on, make offers for, and service your account. These third parties include:

  * Credit reporting agencies
  * Plastic manufacturers
  * Print suppliers
  * Payment processing suppliers
  * Collections and law firms
  * Fraud detection services
  * Mastercard® (and merchants through Mastercard)
  * Call centres
  * Marketing and research companies
  * Credit card Partners
  * Regulators, courts, law enforcement and other government institutions

When you apply for, receive or use one of our Partner cards, Capital One and our Partner may collect, use, disclose and maintain your personal information for certain purposes described in this Privacy Policy and as required to establish, administer and maintain your membership in the Partner program. This applies if you have a Capital One Costco Mastercard; are a SaksFirst Credit cardholder; or are a Hudson’s Bay Mastercard or Hudson’s Bay Credit Card customer.

While Capital One takes all reasonable measures to protect data, there is always inherent risk when providing personal information. We have procedures and practices to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft and unauthorized access. You can also take steps to protect your personal information, like providing us with your new address if you move, and not sending us sensitive information through email.

You can contact Customer Service for general privacy inquiries or concerns. You can also write to our Privacy Office to request access to the personal information we have on file for you; or to raise a privacy concern.

### Table of Contents

### 1\. Privacy Commitment and Personal Information

We collect, use and disclose personal information to operate our business and as required by law. Personal information is information about an identifiable individual, as defined in the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_.

### 2\. Changes to Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes our current privacy practices. We update this Policy on an ongoing basis to ensure consumers, applicants and customers are aware of updates to our privacy practices, to streamline those practices and to comply with applicable laws. Consumers are individuals who are not currently our customers; applicants are individuals who apply to become our customers; and customers are individuals who have been approved, use or have used our products and services in the past. Please visit this site regularly for updates. We will also notify individuals with whom we have a relationship of any material changes that may impact them.

### 3\. Accountability

Our Privacy Officer is responsible for ensuring that we comply with this Policy and applicable privacy laws.

We are responsible for personal information in our possession or custody, as well as personal information transferred to a third party for processing. More details on our third parties are provided below under “Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention”.

### 4\. Information We Collect, and Limiting Collection

Except where information is required to fulfill an identified purpose, you get to decide what information you want to share with us.

**Connecting with us.** We may collect information you provide if you visit or use our website or apps, register or apply for one of our products or services, interact with us through social media or online ads, participate in surveys, or engage with us in any way. We may collect that information for uses as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Information about you.** If you sign up for one of our products or services, depending on the service, we may collect information about your transactions, including purchases, account balances, fees, payment history, parties to transactions and credit card usage. We may collect information from credit reporting agencies and other outside sources to verify financial information about you, such as your employment and credit history. If you give us your SIN, we may use it to identify you with credit reporting agencies and other parties; we may keep this information along with other information about you in our records, even after your account is closed. When you provide authorized user information, we expect that you have authority to consent to its collection, use, and disclosure as outlined in this Policy.

**Digital and online information.** We may collect information from your mobile and online activity; for example, Internet Protocol (IP) address, mobile device ID, application and website use, and history. Cookies (small computer files that a website’s server places on your computer) collect information about your online behaviour. You can set your browser to reject cookies, but this may impair our ability to customize and test your experience, like remembering your preferred language or present province-specific information to you.

**Third party service providers.** We may collect information about you from third parties that we have contracted with, such as credit reporting agencies or affiliates. We may collect publicly available information about you from online sources, or from surveys that you participate in.

**Communication.** When you have a telephone conversation with one of our representatives, your call may be recorded for quality and training purposes, as well as to resolve concerns. If you choose to contact us by email or mail, we may retain your email address, the content of your communication and our response.

### 5\. Identifying Purposes

Capital One clearly identifies the purposes for which personal information is collected, used or disclosed prior to, or at the time of, collection, and as in our cardholder agreement.

**We may use your information to contact you.** Your information allows us to contact you by various methods, including mail, email, SMS message, and telephone at the contact points you’ve provided to us. We will contact you to respond to your questions, proactively provide you with information about your account(s) with us, inform you about our products and services, and update you on changes to our website, mobile app, and other digital services we provide. We may use your information to send you important updates about your application status and account opening disclosures, and important or useful messages about your account(s). When you communicate online or by email, you should be aware that sending information over the internet isn’t secure, as it can be intercepted and/or manipulated and retransmitted.

**We may use your information to authenticate you.** With your information, we can confirm your identity by sharing your information with the credit agency to authenticate you when you apply for a product or service, to verify that it’s you we are speaking with when you call our Customer Service number to discuss your account, or identify you when you visit us online or on our mobile app.

**We may use your information to assess your creditworthiness.** With your information, we can assess your creditworthiness to determine your eligibility for products and services, and process your application(s). This information is helpful for us to offer you product choices that are suitable for you. In order to do this, we will provide your information to, and collect information about you from credit reporting agencies (refer to section 7 Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention for information on third party sharing).

**We may use your information to service you.** Your information may be used to maintain, service, process, analyze, audit and collect on your account(s). For example, loyalty reward numbers and program statuses are used to align your account with cobranded credit card loyalty rewards providers. We may use your information to service your mobile account, optimize our website, perform analytics, and provide you with a unique user experience. We may also send notifications and support mobile payments with this information. When we issue you a new card, we may provide your new account information to facilitate your payments, pursuant to industry standards (refer to section 7 Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention for information on third party sharing).

**We may use your information to make improvements.** We may use your personal information to evaluate existing products and services, develop new products and services, drive strategy and improve the customer experience we offer. Information we collect is also valuable for our quality and servicing training programs.

We also customize our website and mobile applications based on information collected, and use that information to understand and deliver products and services that you, and others who are similar to you, may find useful. The information is used to better understand our website and mobile application activity, and how users interact with our digital sites. It’s also used to monitor and improve our website and mobile applications.

**We may use your information to prevent fraud.** We may use your information to assess fraud and other risks to you and Capital One, and to protect consumers, applicants and customers from identity theft, fraud and unauthorized account access. When investigating fraud, we may ask for identification documents (such as a Canadian driver’s licence, Canadian passport, birth certificate, utility bill or bank statement, or other forms of identification).

**We may use your information to serve you offers, advertising and marketing.** Elements of your personal information may be used to determine your suitability, or to directly communicate with you, for targeted advertising, marketing, promotions, rewards programs, research or contests. You may see advertisements for our products and services on our website, mobile applications or on third-party websites, based on your online or mobile activity and information you’ve shared with third parties.

We may use your personal information to identify you on third-party platforms you already use (such as Facebook and Twitter) and serve you ads through their marketing platforms. We may also use your information to identify you on third-party platforms (such as Facebook and Google), and then use the algorithms of those platforms to find other people with similar characteristics.

Where your credit score is used for the purposes of advertising, express opt-in consent will be captured from you at the time of collection.

We may prevent you from seeing Capital One offers that are unsuitable for you, based on the information we know about you. For example, if you are already a customer, we don’t want to serve you ads for products and services you already have with us.

You can opt out of offers, advertising and marketing uses of your information, and opt out of the use of cookies by following the instructions in the “Consent” section below.

**We may use your information to report.** We may share application and transaction information with consumer reporting agencies and other parties who have financial, employment or business dealings with you.

If you apply for a credit product, communicate with us or provide personal information to us in any way, you acknowledge your consent for personal information collection, use and disclosure as set out in this Policy, applicable laws and industry standards. If we want to use your information for a purpose that was not disclosed at the time of initial consent, consent will be sought at the time of this new purpose.

**Updating consent.** Subject to legal and contractual restrictions, you can, with reasonable notice to Capital One, withdraw your consent for use and disclosure of your personal information, other than that which is required for us to maintain your account and to provide services for which you were approved.

**Opt out of mail, email and phone marketing.** You can request that we don’t contact you for advertising, marketing, promotions, rewards programs, research or contests, by updating your privacy preferences. You should know that withdrawing your consent in these instances may result in you missing out on offers specific to your account, like credit limit increases.

To update your privacy preferences for specific accounts, please contact the following numbers:

  * Capital One credit card: 1-800-481-3239 

  * Capital One Costco Mastercard: 1-800-723-3500 

  * Hudson’s Bay Mastercard and Hudson’s Bay Credit Card: 1-877-889-0725 

  * SaksFirst Credit Card and Saks Fifth Avenue Credit Card: 1-855-725-7222 

To opt out of the Capital One email marketing list only, [visit our email opt-out site](https://www.capitalone.ca/SSP/preferences/en/ "Link opens in a new window").

You must opt out of the use of cookies separately.

**Opt out of cookies used for Online Behavioural Advertising (“OBA”).** You can adjust your browser to reject cookies by clicking on the “AdChoices” link embedded in many of our ads. We subscribe to the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada’s Self-Regulatory Principles for OBA. These principles promote consumers’ awareness and choice about how their information is used for OBA. You can opt out of the use of your browsing habits for OBA – just [visit the AdChoices website](http://youradchoices.ca/choices "Link opens in a new window") provided by the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada, and use the opt-out mechanism.

Capital One limits use, disclosure and retention of personal information to the purposes we identify, and as required by applicable laws.

**Third parties.** We do not sell or rent customer lists or personal information to others. We may share your personal information with service providers who perform services for your account on our behalf (such as credit reporting agencies, card manufacturers, print suppliers, payment processing businesses, marketing, research, call centres, and other services as required to service you). Our contracts with third parties include obligations to protect your personal information, and third parties must meet our rigorous privacy standards. When you engage with other companies directly, or contact us through their platforms, their use of the information they collect from you is subject to the terms of their privacy policies. We may share your information with regulators, courts or other institutions as required by law.

**Basic information disclosed to third parties for the use as described under ‘Identifying Purposes’**

  1. **Credit reporting agencies** – We may share your information with the credit agency/agencies to make a decision about your application and other decisions about your account. Information shared may include the following: name; address; SIN; phone; credit card plastic number; account terms; date of birth; transaction records; credit information; customer performance data

  2. **Plastic manufacturers** – We may share your information with the plastic manufacturer to issue your credit card(s). Information shared may include the following: credit card number; name; and address.

  3. **Print suppliers** – We may share your information with print suppliers to print letters and statements pertaining to your account. Information shared may include the following: credit card plastic number; name and address; and previous period transactions.

  4. **Payment processing suppliers** – We may share your information with our payments processing suppliers to process your transactions and payments. Information shared may include the following: transaction information; account number; bank from which monies were extracted; and the name on the account of the bank.

  5. **Collections and law firms** – We may share your information to help us collect a debt owed to us by you. Information shared may include the following: contact and financial information.

  6. **Fraud detection services** – We may use third parties to monitor your transactions to identify fraudulent activity on your account.

  7. **Mastercard** – As part of the payment network, and pursuant to the Mastercard Automatic Billing Updater (ABU) as amended from time to time or pursuant to other industry standards, we may update and/or provide information regarding your credit card or account. ABU facilitates the secure transmission of account updates to card-on-file and recurring payments merchants. ABU helps reduce the number of declined transactions due to card expirations, lost or stolen cards, and other account changes.

  8. **Call centres and quality assurance providers** – We may share access to your account information maintained on Capital One systems, with call centres to service your account and provide you with customer support. We may share your customer experience with a third party to evaluate how we are doing, and ensure we are complying with applicable laws and regulations.

  9. **Marketing and research companies** – We may share your information to understand and deliver products, services and offers that you, and others who are similar to you, may find useful. We may also share your information to block offers that you won’t find useful. This includes digital affiliates.

  10. **Regulators, courts, law enforcement and other government institutions** – We may share your information to resolve concerns and as required by law.

**Capital One Mastercard for Costco members.** When you apply for and maintain a card, you (i) authorize us to disclose your personal information to Costco Wholesale Canada Ltd. (“Costco”) and its affiliates for the purposes of maintaining your card account and establishing and administering your Costco membership; (ii) authorize us to inform Costco of our decision to issue or deny you a card; (iii) authorize Costco to provide us with your Costco membership photo and membership number, both of which will appear on the card; (iv) authorize Costco to provide us with your membership start date and type and status of your Costco membership; and (v) authorize Costco to provide us with your resale permit number, if applicable. Unless you tell us otherwise, we may also share information with Costco for the purposes of offering or communicating with you about promotional offers or other products and services.

**SaksFirst Credit cardholders.** Capital One provides and administers the SaksFirst Credit Card and the Saks Fifth Avenue Credit Card, and Saks and its affiliates endorse the card. When you have a SaksFirst Credit Card and the Saks Fifth Avenue Credit Card, you have a relationship with both Saks and Capital One. When you apply for, receive or use a card, Capital One and Saks each collect, use, disclose and maintain your personal information for certain purposes. Saks collects and uses your information to provide you with goods and services, to comply with legal and regulatory requirements, and as otherwise permitted by law. Saks may also share your information with Capital One to help in maintaining your account. An integral feature of your account is that you will earn SaksFirst points on every eligible purchase made using your card. When your SaksFirst Credit Card account is opened, you will be automatically enrolled in the SaksFirst Rewards Program. Where your information relates to your SaksFirst Rewards Account, Saks also collects and uses it to establish and administer such account. For more information, please review the Saks Fifth Avenue (Canada) Privacy Policy. From time to time, Saks may amend or update its Privacy Policy. [Visit the Saks Fifth Avenue website](http://www.saksfifthavenue.com/Canada/PrivacyPolicy_EN.jsp "Link opens in a new window") to get the most up-to-date version of the Privacy Policy.

**Hudson’s Bay Mastercard andHudson’s Bay Credit Card customers.** Capital One provides and administers the Hudson’s Bay Mastercard and the Hudson’s Bay Credit Card, and Hudson’s Bay Company and its affiliates endorse the cards. When you have a Hudson’s Bay Mastercard or a Hudson’s Bay Credit Card, you have a relationship with both Hudson’s Bay Company and Capital One. When you apply for, receive or use a card, Capital One and Hudson’s Bay Company each collect, use, disclose and maintain your personal information for certain purposes. Hudson’s Bay Company collects and uses your information to provide you with goods and services, to comply with legal and regulatory requirements, and as otherwise permitted by law. Hudson’s Bay Company may also share your information with Capital One to help in maintaining your account. An integral feature of your account is that you are enrolled in the Hudson’s Bay Rewards program and can earn Hudson’s Bay Rewards points on eligible purchases made using your card. Where your information relates to your Hudson’s Bay Rewards account, Hudson’s Bay Company also collects and uses it to establish and administer your Hudson’s Bay Rewards account. From time to time, Hudson’s Bay Company may amend or update the Hudson’s Bay Company Privacy Policy. [Visit the Hudson’s Bay Company website](http://www3.hbc.com/privacy/ "Link opens in a new window") for the most up-to-date version of the Hudson’s Bay Company Privacy Policy.

**Assignees.** We may, at any time, sell, transfer or assign any or all of our rights to our Canadian business, including our interests, rights or obligations regarding your account(s) with us. If we do so, we may share your personal information with prospective purchasers, transferees or assignees.

**Information processed outside Canada.** Your personal information may be stored and processed at our corporate offices in the U.S. or with approved third parties within the U.S. or elsewhere.

If a third party processes or stores information outside Canada, foreign governments, courts or regulatory agencies may therefore be able to obtain such personal information through the laws of the foreign jurisdiction.

### 8\. Accuracy

Capital One ensures personal information is as accurate, complete and up to date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used.

If you believe that the personal information we have about you isn’t accurate or complete, please contact us by updating your information through online banking, by calling the customer service number on the back of your card, or by writing to the Privacy Office. If you move or change your phone number or email address, update your address with us.

### 9\. Safeguards

Capital One uses procedures and practices appropriate to the sensitivity of personal information to protect against loss, theft and unauthorized access. Access to your information is restricted to those individuals and parties who require access.

For example, we have physical security (such as restricted access to our offices and secure storage), electronic protection (such as passwords and encryption) and safe business practices (such as customer authentication when you call us). We also train our staff on how to safeguard personal information.

While Capital One takes all reasonable measures to protect data, there is always inherent risk when providing personal information. You can help us safeguard your information too. If you contact us through email or social media, you should avoid sending highly sensitive information, such as your banking information or full credit card number. If someone ‘representing Capital One’ contacts you and requests your personal or financial information, and you are suspicious, you can always contact us to confirm that the request was legitimate. We also recommend that you use unique and strong passwords for your online account(s) and that you don’t share your passwords with anyone.

You can write to our Privacy Office to request access to the personal information we have on file for you. We will provide you with the personal information we have, subject to certain considerations specified by law. Some of the information we have on you, like your contact information and transactions, is available on your account statements easily accessed by you through online banking.

**You can contact Customer Service for general privacy inquiries or concerns:**

To speak to a Customer Service Representative: 1-800-481-3239

**For more information about our Policy, or to raise a privacy concern, please contact our Privacy Office at the following address:**

Attention: Privacy Officer  
Capital One Canada  
P.O. Box 508, Stn D  
Scarborough, ON M1R 5L6
